# JORDAN ELL

 $(250) \cdot 415 \cdot 9542 \diamond \text{jordan.ell7@gmail.com}$ 

2701 Gosworth Rd Apt-303 & Victoria, British Columbia, Canada

I am a Computer Scientist and have been involved in both software development in industry, as well as computer science and software engineering research in academia. My broad range of contributions to the feild allow me to tackle many problems from work flow to architecture to software optimization. I have also been involved in large scale data security measures and optimizations which brings experience directly from the feild.

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of Victoria

June 2013

B.S. in Computer Science with Software Engineering

Jamie Cassels Undergraduate Research Scholarship (2012)

Presidents Scholarship (2008, 2012)

Graduating GPA: 7.73 (3.9)

## University of Victoria

June 2014

MSc. in Computer Science GPA: Unknown at time

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## University of Victoria

May 2012 - Present

Victoria, BC

Software Engineering Researcher

- · Researching in the realm of socio-technical congruence with applications in awareness among developers.
- · Data mining large scale structured and unstructured data to create technical and social dependency networks inside of software projects.
- · Creation of bug prediction tools for socially induced failures.
- · Creation of source code analysis tools in order to extract technical dependencies.
- · Applications developed using Java, PostgreSQL, HTML, Javascript, CSS, and AJAX.

#### IBM

September 2010 - April 2011

Vancouver, BC

 $Environment\ Support$ 

- · Orchestrated the deployment and maintenance of Linix, Windows, and AIX, project servers.
- · Creation of a single sign on authentication system across Unix and Linux platforms to increase accountability and security.
- · Creation of an OS and middle ware patch management system to track required and applied software patches on servers across multiple levels of security.
- · Creation of automatic tools to ensure server backup systems made adjustments as necessary to complete backup cycles.

#### James Evans and Associates

May 2010 - September 2010

Oracle Developer

Victoria, BC

- · Developed Oracle Forms as a front end for pension management systems.
- · Creation of "Smart Letters" which use an Oracle Database to automatically generate a large set of template letters with stakeholder information.
- · Created and managed large SQL scripts / libraries for maintaining sets of data in a Oracle database.

#### COMPETENCIES

Change Leadership - During my time at IBM, I had led a change in a large portion of IT infrastructure centred around access management and security. This position allowed me to create a new vision for our policies and technical tools and follow through by creating and supporting this vision.

Analytical Thinking - During my time at James Evan and Associates, I had opportunities to organize a database schema. This involved taking a very abstract view and breaking it down in several smaller and finer grain components to create a successful schema.

Conceptual Thinking - At IBM, while in charge of data backup procedures, often backups would fail for non obvious reasons. In order to solve these issues, complex event chains would often have to be found in order to address the root of the problem.

Long Term Focus - while implementing a single sign on authentication for improved accountability, often staff would complain about a now extra step needed on their part. The long term focus to avoid these debates was to show how increased accountability leads to higher security standards and data integrity.

#### KNOWLEDGE

Java, C++, C#, C, Python, Ruby Computer Languages

Protocols & APIs .NET, SDL, OpenGL, XML, JSON, REST **Databases** MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle Database, DB2

Tools Git, Svn, CVS, Eclipse, Visual Studio

OS Linux (Ubuntu, Fedora, RedHat), Windows, OSX

#### PROJECTS

All projects available on GitHub at: github.com/jordanell

## Impact!

Sole Developer

September 2012 - Present

- · An awareness tool used for developers in small to medium size projects written in Java, HTML, CSS, Javascript and AJAX.
- Provides automatic social recommendations that are based on technical dependencies among developers in the project's source code.
- · Allows developers to subscribe to informational "Streams" which track files, objects, methods and people.

# **STCharts**

September 2012 - April 2013

Sole Developer

- · A socio-technical congruence awareness visualization tool written in Java, HTML, CSS, Javascript and AJAX.
- · Developed as part of a fellow researcher's PhD.
- · Allows researchers to input a Git repository as well as a Jira issue tracking URL, which then get analysed for socio-technical congruence over the projects lifetime and is then displayed using a web front end making use of Google Charts.